calling yourself a junior you're not a
junior you know you're not really a
senior either in fact you look this is a
biggest complaint I have had about the
titles anyway right so let's not even
get into the whole thing about the
titles never actually matching the work
that you do the number of rolls the
number of hats you wear whatever in tech
nine times out of 10 the job you have
the title is going to be completely
unrelated and it's not just in Tech it's
all over the place in fact there have
been a couple companies that have
explored paying people par role and
allowing them to wear multiple roles at
the same time so they have roles and
then they would pay and be compensated
and everything and the skills would
match the role that they had and if
you're sort of a overly analytical
person that really appeals to you it
does me but the one thing that never
applies is the word Junior it just
doesn't apply I have worked with so many
people who kept calling thems a junior
because of their impostor syndrome which
we'll talk about
and so and but they were better than
people who I had been working with for
10 years depending on what thing it is
they're doing software engineering which
is a horrible title all by itself you're
not an engineer you're a developer just
call yourself that or a programmer we
can fight about that all day we're not
going to fight about that the point is
stop calling yourself a
junior if someone is asking you if
you're applying for junior jobs you're
talking about say I am a programmer I am
a developer what kind of kind of
developer are you well I'm a i i
primarily program in go and python so if
you're a developer by the way and you're
programming in one language you're not a
developer honestly a developer is
somebody who has experience across the
board and can develop software
Solutions and the language
implementation is not directly relevant
to getting the solution in fact that's a
separate video but if you're going to
call yourself a developer that means you
need to be able to learn any language
any time depending on what you're doing
and you might have a preference or an
expertise in a particular language like
I do with go any I want Developer jobs
that have go in them I am an
infrastructure engineer and right now
80% of my time is spent programming a go
because because that's what we need to
make our API the point is and I'm not a
junior I'm not a senior either I have X
number of experience years of experience
and I have this much code that I can
produce to do the trust there's another
video I talk about where it talks about
the nature of employment and how it's
built on trust and trust is driven by
the employer deciding if you are junior
so one person's junior is another
person's you know senior and and I'm I'm
talking from the perspective of the
person giving you the
job right so so you know it's an
evaluation that needs to be made that
needs to be Quantified and the person
who's doing the quantifying of that
who's measuring you to see if you
qualify for that position
they are going to have very specific
criteria about what it means whether you
can meet the job whether you can get the
job or do the job the whole thing for
them it's going to be different and if
you if you
mistakenly you know call yourself a
junior when really you actually have
just enough stuff to be able to do the
thing I have a I have a story about this
I'm going to give you a quick story I
was hired as a kubernetes uh
infrastructure engineer specifically to
deal with kubernetes I had had literally
zero years or months of experience with
kubernetes and I told them that straight
up if I had said oh I I don't have any
kubernetes experience or if I had called
myself a junior infrastructure engineer
with regard to kubernetes I didn't so
what I did is I capitalized on the
things that I did in the interview I was
able to talk about the things that I had
done the successes that I had done and I
didn't call myself a junior or anything
like that I just stated the facts like
what are the things I had done how did I
do them you know what were my challenges
what were my failures what were my
successes what felt really good what
were the exact line item metrics on how
much money was saved or how much these
are the things that allow a person who's
evaluating you to measure
you and if you slap a junior label on
yourself or even a senior label on
yourself prematurely one person God you
how many times I've met a senior
software engineer who doesn't know what
the hell they're
doing with regard to a particular
problem or a particular solution because
senior software engineering is a pretty
big area you know what I mean and it's
it's not the kind of thing that you want
to just you know I the point is that you
when you're doing these kind of things
stop labeling yourself and if somebody
else is going to label you that's fine
that's up to them let them do the
labeling that's the takeaway let them do
the labeling you are a developer you're
a programmer you're an infrastructure
person you're perhaps a security person
in in in terms of security instead of
saying you're a junior security here's
another way to say it okay I'm going me
give you some specific ways to replace
the word Junior you can say I am a go
programmer with two years of experience
programming go on the following
projects notice how I didn't say junior
I am a go programmer with one year
experience including this I am a CO I'm
a go programmer I am a rust programmer
with I personally am a rust programmer
with you know three months of experience
programming rust am I a junior rust
programmer no I'm probably not even a
programmer but again the point is that
that determination is not up to me to
make that determination is up to the
person who wants me to do something for
them that whole trust you know employer
relationship so don't sell yourself
short stick with the facts stick with
the facts and tell people what they need
to know to make their own decision about
whether you are a junior or not but ban
the word from your vocabulary